Monterrey, Nuevo León

Claudio B. Rodríguez

claudiordgz

+52 1 (81) 13490166

- **U** 01 52 8119358682
- claudiordgz.com
- **y** @claudiordgz
- github.com/claudiordgz
- StackOverflow Profile

Objective

Results are not everything. There are also many factors to take into account, like being able to change over time, performing multiple similar tasks, unit testing, automatic build and deploy packages, and the one factor most places do not consider, making small independent projects to allow further expansion of workforce, all this without changing the time constraints.

Software Development is my craft, and I am proud to be part of it to help my customers convert their desires to reality, including the most important thing of all, their brand. A software solution is just a solution, but when pairing it with a brand, it creates an experience. We use complex algorithms, elaborate data structures, and contrived concurrency problems, all to protect the customer's brand.

I want to be part in helping Amazon develop its brand.









Professional Experience

Epicor Software

June 2014 - Current

Project: LaserCat 3

- Created C++ Cross platform tool to check server for updates of Prod-
- Created installation Architecture using WiX Toolset, focusing on adding value and responding to change.
- Created C++ tools to create WiX Dialogs using relative positioning, reducing time between changes.

AMI GE Automation & Control Innovation

June 2012 - June 2014

Project: DigitARC PX3

- Reduced size of files being logged using Audio Compression by %60.
- Developed C++, Bash and Batch unit tests, successfully prevented errors when changes to crucial features of the system were done, automated it in CruiseControl.
- Provided Customer Support on any issue related, and created tutorials for our customers that reduced customer support from 6 man-hr average p/week to 2 man-hr p/month average.
- Rewrote the Product Manual in LaTeX, added to build system. Modify once, publish on different places, automated it in CruiseControl.

Tools

- Git
- SVN
- Autotools
- Windows
- Linux
- QNX

Professional Experience

AMI GE Automation & Control Innovation

June 2012 - Current

Project: DigitARC PX3

- Developed Python Tool to analyze the PX3's communication using another software.
- Found bug in major feature, redesigned that part, add unit tests to it, automated it in CruiseControl.

Project: Visual KB / SmartArc

- Bug fixes of MFC C++ Legacy Code, specifically invalid memory errors.
- Created clear and specific tutorials for our customers.
- · Maintained manual up to speed.
- Rebuilt the installer using InstallShield 2010, automated it in CruiseControl.

GE Consumer & Industrial 2008

- Developed 147 scheduled maintenance tasks, one for each equipment, deployed and trained maintenance and production personnel.
- Trained Purchasing Leader, Technology Leader, Maintenance Leader, and Production Leader in the use of PMPro tool so they could maximize their benefits from Preventive Maintenance.

Education

Tec de Monterrey, N.L.

Master in Science with Specialty in Intelligent Systems (2010)

- Member of Professorship of Applied Intelligent Agents in Videogames.
- Specialization in Particle Swarm Optimization and Emergent Behavior Algorithms.

Tec de Monterrey Campus Sonora Norte Mechatronics Engineer (2004-2008)

Hermosillo, Son

Projects

Phoenix2D Project

Open Source project to allow students to develop their own Player to compete in RoboCup Soccer Simulation. Currently redesigning implementation.

- Created build system using GNU Autotools.
- Created website.
- Create documentation.

Ad Generator

• Developing Cross Platform App to Allow easier Ad Generation for multiple web platforms.